Liam Ayscough

46 Cambeak Close, Bransholme Hull, HU7 4ES Telephone: 07756643989

Email: LiamAyscough@gmail.com

PROFILE:

I am a hard-working and motivated software developer who always strives for success. With over 7 years' experience in the field, I always seek to improve my knowledge of IT systems wherever possible and enthusiastically welcome new challenges and problems with a strong willingness to learn.

SKILLS:

- Knowledge of using ASP.NET to create web-based applications.
- Knowledge of HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
- Knowledge of creating desktop applications using WinForms and WPF.
- Knowledge of Xamarin Forms to create Android applications.
- Knowledge of Git source control via Visual Studio, GitHub, SourceTree, and GitKraken.
- Knowledge of Agile development paradigms including Scrum.
- Knowledge of SQL and relational database design.
- Familiar with Azure DevOps.
- Can effectively work as part of a team, with excellent time management skills.

HOBBIES AND INTERESTS:

I also like to create software in my own time too, whether it's simply coding for fun or finishing off pet projects. I usually like to throw myself in the deep end and try to learn something completely new.

When not sitting at my PC I like playing football at the weekends, which has improved my confidence and communication skills while also allowing me to appreciate the value of teamwork.

EDUCATION:

2014 - 2017

University of Hull	BSC (Hons) Computer Science	Overall: 2:1
	User Interface Design	72/100
	Systems Analysis	70/100
	Programming 1	70/100
	Programming 2	68/100
	Human Computer Interaction	75/100
	Database Techniques	69/100
2010 – 2014		
Wilberforce College	Business BTEC level 3 Extended Diploma	DMM
	IT BTEC level 3 Extended Diploma	D*DD
2004 – 2010		
David Lister School	8 GCSEs grades A-C including English and Mathematics	S A – C

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY:

June 2023 - CURRENT Software Developer, NEC / Zetron, Hull

- Joined as part of the 'Connect' team who are responsible for developing and maintaining the
 train dispatcher system used by London Underground. Contributing to the rewrite project which
 involved porting legacy Delphi applications into C# WPF, ensuring that code is unit tested and
 writing any accompanying documentation.
- Liaising with customers including Motorola to provide progress reports.

March 2022 - May 2023

Software Developer, ESP Systex, Hull

- Responsible for maintaining and updating the company's ASP.NET web-based systems. These
 include APIs, Portals, and a CRM used by local authorities across the UK to manage travel card
 applications.
- Part of the 'Projects' team who are responsible for estimating and implementing new features
 received through change requests. Ensuring that estimates are accurate and that other
 members within the team including the PM, BA, QA are informed about the upcoming features
 and what it involves. Once a feature has been done ensuring Release branches are created and
 conflicts are resolved.
- Using SQL to perform CRUD operations as well as altering stored procedures on databases throughout the QA, UAT, STG, LIVE environments using Microsoft SQL Server Management Studio.
- Contributed to the teams fully green RAG status which had only been achieved 5 years prior.

June 2017 - March 2022 Software Developer, Leisure Electronics, Hull

- Responsible for maintaining and updating the company's legacy Xamarin software installed on the bingo machines. The software would allow customers to browse and play installed games on both Windows and Android tablet devices.
- Successfully produced an Android and Windows game using Xamarin and OpenGL that has been deployed in the field and can be played at gambling establishments across the UK and Ireland.
- Successfully established a Greenfield project from initial conception to distribution for customers in the UK and Netherlands. This project would allow customers to play and manage bingo games in small – medium sized venues with the aid of a Windows tablet (WPF) and Android TV box (Xamarin).
- Contributed to the companies growing online presence by helping develop a PWA using the Vue.js framework. This would allow customers to find local venues using the Google maps API and eventually allowed customers to chat to each other using Google Firebase.